The Polish Club, Inc. CPAA 10.14
Connecticut Polish American Archives
The Polish Club, Inc.
1979-1996
CPAA 10.14
Connecticut Polish American Archives
2.0 Linear feet
The Polish Club, Inc. was a social club organized by group of Poles active in the Bridgeport area to promote Polish culture. The club closely cooperated with the Polish Program at Sacred Heart University in Bridgeport. The Polish Club was officially incorporated in 1979 and was very active until the late 1990's, yet later its activities diminished. Collection consists of material documenting club activities from 1979 till 1996.
Chorobik, Mary
The Polish Club, Inc..
Biographical/Historical note
The Polish Club, Inc. was established in 1979 by a group of Poles from the Bridgeport area to support the Polish Studies program at the Sacred Heart University (SHU). The official registered name of the club was The Polish Club Inc., however the name “The Polish Club Inc. at Sacred Heart University” was also used in formal publications. The mission of the club was to promote higher education, provide scholarships and to disseminate knowledge about Poland. Membership was open to any permanent resident of the U.S. who was invited by another club member. The Club was an affiliate member of a larger national organization - the American Council for Polish Culture. The Club organized many cultural events, including exhibits, lectures, concerts, movie showings and supported events at the SHU, especially Polish language classes. The Club was very active throughout the 1990's but then its activities diminished. It became difficult to attract new members and to organize interesting programs with fewer resources. Mary Chorobik was a long time member of the club and held various positions, including presidency for 15 years. She collected documentation of the club activities from 1979 till 1996. She was a tireless promoter of Polish language and culture. Mrs. Chorobik organized many events and participated in conventions at the national level. Her daughter, Honore Radshaw, donated club records in June of 2010.
Arrangement note
The original arrangement of the material was kept.
Related Archival Materials note
For related material see the following collections:
Amarican Council for Polish Culture records. CPAA 96-03
Polish Cultural Club of Greater Hartford records. CPAA 86-30
Scope and Contents note
The collection consists of correspondence, minutes, newsletters, programs, pamphlets and photographs documenting club activities. It includes extensive collection of clippings related to club activities and other activities related to Poland and Polonia on the local and national level.
Conditions Governing Access note
The collection is open for research.
American Council for Polish Culture; Attu, Battle of, Alaska, 1943; Clippings.; Correspondence.; Minutes.; Pamphlets.; Phtotographs.; Polish Americans -- Connecticut; Polish Americans Societies, etc.; Scrapbook
- The Polish Club, Inc. - Articles of Incorporation, 1979; box 1 fol. 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - tax exempt status, 1979-1986; box 1 fol. 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - financial statements, 1981-1990; box 1 fol. 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - financial statements for IRS, 1980-1989; box 1 fol. 4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - monthly financial statements, 1989-2000; box 1 fol. 5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - President book (handwritten), 1979-1986; box 1 fol. 6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - scholarship forms and applications, 1988-1994; box 1 fol. 7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - minutes of meetings, 1987-1989; box 1 fol. 8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - minutes of meetings (handwritten), 1991-1994; box 1 fol. 9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - correspondence, 1981-1983; box 1 fol. 10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - scrapbook, 1979-1982; box 1 fol. 10A (Box 1, Folder 10A)
  General note
  Scrapbooks contain correspondence, minutes, memos, clippings, programs, and photgraphs.
- The Polish Club, Inc. - scrapbook, 1983-1984; box 1 fol. 11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - scrapbook, 1985-1986; box 1 fol. 12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - scrapbook, 1987-1988; box 1 fol. 13 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - scrapbook, 1989-1990; box 1 fol. 14 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - scrapbook, 1989-1991; box 1 fol. 15 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - scrapbook, 1991-1992; box 1 fol. 16 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - scrapbook, 1993-1994; box 1 fol. 18 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - scrapbook, 1995-1996; box 1 fol. 19 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - membership list, 1980-1998; box 2 fol. 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - meeting attendance list, 1981-1986; box 2 fol. 2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - 10th Anniversary Celebration, guest book, October 1989; box 2 fol. 3 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - Polish language classes and scholarship fund at Sacred Heart University, 1986-1991; box 2 fol. 4 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - Cultural Events Committee, flyers, pamphlets, photographs, programs, 1987-1991; box 2 fol. 5 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - Cultural announcements from various organizations, 1980-1995; box 2 fol. 6 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - Project Washington, list of donors, 1987-1988; box 2 fol. 6 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - Project Washington, fundraising efforts, publicity, clippings, donations, 1987-1992; box 2 fol. 8 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - Press releases and clippings, 1986-1987; box 2 fol. 9 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - Press releases and clippings, 1987-1989; box 2 fol. 10 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - Christmas party donations, 1986-1989; box 2 fol. 11 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - International Folk Festival participation, 1986-1992; box 2 fol. 12 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - Grudka Ziemi, program, press release, clippings, 1991; box 2 fol. 13 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - Correspondence with Polish Heritage Society of Bridgeport, 1984-1991; box 2 fol. 14 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - ACPC Convention in Pultusk, Poland, 1991; box 2 fol.15 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - ACPC Convention in San Francisco, CA, 1990; box 2 fol.16 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - ACPC Convention, Philadelphia, PA, 1989; box 2 fol. 17 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - ACPC Convention, Hartford, CT, 1988; box 2 fol.18 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - ACPC Convention, Ypsilanti, MI, 1987; box 2 fol.19 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - ACPC Convention, Alliance College, PA, 1986; box 2 fol.20 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - ACPC Convention, Buffalo, NY, 1985; box 2 fol.21 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - ACPC cultural events, 1988-1995; box 2 fol.21 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - State of Connecticut General Assembly official citation for club's recognition, May 7, 2003; box 3; Box 3 contains various oversized memorabilia. (Box 3)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - The Black Madonna image, framed., box 3 (Box 3)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - Krakow, Rynek Glowny, framed drawing, 1992; box 3 (Box 3)
- The Polish Club, Inc. - The Joy of Writing of Wislawa Szymborska, poster, 1997; box 3 (Box 3)